today we will talk about deep
今天我们将深入讨论
reinforcement learning the question we
强化学习我们的问题
would like to explore it's to which
想探索这是 哪个
degree we can teach systems to act to
我们可以教导系统采取行动
perceive and act in this world from data
从数据中感知并 在这个世界中 行动
so let's take a step back and think of
让我们 退一步 想一想
what is the full range of tasks then
那么什么是完整的任务
artificial intelligence system needs to
人工智能系统需要
accomplish here's the stack from top to
完成这里的堆栈 从顶部到
bottom top the input bottom output the
底部输入底部输出
environment at the top the world that
世界顶尖的环境
the agent is operating in sensed by
代理人在感觉到的运作
sensors taking in the world outside and
传感器在外面和外面的世界
converting it to raw data interpretable
将其转换为原始数据可解释
by machines sensor data and from that
通过机器传感器数据和从那里
raw sensor data you extract features you
您提取的原始传感器数据为您提供
extract structure from that data such
从该 数据 ，例如提取物结构
that you can input it make sense of it
您可以输入它来理解 它
discriminate separate understand the
歧视分开理解
data and as we discussed you form higher
数据和我们讨论过的你形成的更高
and higher order representations a
和更高阶的表示a
hierarchy of representations based on
基于表示的层次
which the machine learning techniques
哪台机器学习技巧
can then be applied once the machine
然后可以在机器上应用
learning techniques the understanding as
学习技巧的理解为
I mentioned converts the data into
我提到过将数据转换成
features into higher order
功能更高阶
representations and into simple
表示和简单
actionable useful information we
可行的有用信息我们
aggregate that information into
将该信息汇总到
knowledge we take the pieces of
知识，我们采取的碎片
knowledge extracted from the data
从数据中提取的知识
through the machine learning techniques
通过机器学习技巧
and to build a taxonomy a library of
并建立一个分类法 的图书馆
knowledge and with that knowledge we
知识和 我们的知识
reason an aging estas to reason to
推理老化的理由
aggregate to connect pieces of data it's
聚合以连接它的 数据
seen in the recent past or the distant
在最近看到的还是遥远的
past to make sense of the world that's
过去去了解那个 世界
operating in and finally to make a plan
经营并最终制定计划
of how to act in that world based on its
如何在这个世界的基础上采取行动
objectives based on what it wants to
基于它想做的目标
accomplished as I mentioned a simple but
完成后 我提到了一个简单的但是
commonly accepted definition of
普遍接受 的 定义
intelligence is a system that's able to
智能是一个能够的系统
accomplish complex goals so system
完成复杂的目标所以系统
that's operating in the environment in
那是在环境中运作的
this world must have a goal must have an
这个世界上一定有一个目标 必须有一个
objective function a reward function and
目标函数奖励功能和
based on that it forms a plan and takes
基于它形成一个计划并采取
action and because there operates in
行动，因为有运作
many cases in the physical world
在物理世界中的许多情况
it must have tools effectors with which
它必须有工具效应器
it applies the actions to change
它适用于改变的行动
something about the world that's the
关于这个世界的事情
full stack of an artificial intelligence
满满 的人工智能
system that acts in the world and the
在世界 和 世界上行动的制度
question is what kind of task can such a
问题是这样的任务是什么样的
system take on what kind of task can an
系统承担什么样的任务可以
artificial intelligence system learn as
人工智能系统学习 为
we understand AI today we will talk
我们今天理解AI，我们会谈
about the advancement of deeper
关于 更深层次的进步
enforcement learning approaches and some
执法学习方法和一些
of the fascinating ways it's able to
能够 做到的迷人方式
take much of the stack and treat it as
占用大部分堆栈 并将 其 视为
an end-to-end learning problem but we
一个端到端的学习问题，但我们
look at games we look at simple
看看我们看简单的游戏
formalized worlds while it's still
形式化的世界， 而它 仍然存在
impressive beautiful and unprecedented
令人印象深刻的美丽
accomplishments it's nevertheless formal
成就是 正式 还是
tasks can we then move beyond games and
我们可以将任务超越游戏
into expert tasks of medical diagnosis
进入医学诊断的专家任务
of design and into natural language and
设计和自然语言和
finally the human level tasks of emotion
最后是人类层面的情感任务
imagination consciousness let's once
想象力意识让我们一次
again review the stack in practicality
再次审查堆栈的实用性
in the tools we have the input for
在我们输入的工具中
robots operating in the world from cars
汽车在世界上运行的机器人
to humanoid to drones as light our
人形无人机 对我们来说 是无人机
camera radar GPS stereo cameras audio
相机雷达GPS立体声相机音频
microphone networking for communication
用于通信的麦克风网络
and the various ways to measure
和各种方法来 衡量
kinematics with IMU
IMU的运动学
the raw sensory data is then processed
然后处理原始传感数据
features of form to representations are
表征 形式的特征 是
formed and multiple higher and higher
形成多个越来越高
order representations
订单陈述
that's what deep learning gets us before
这就是深度学习之前带给我们的东西
neural networks before the advent of
神经 网络出现之前
before the recent successes of neural
在最近的神经成功之前
networks to go deeper and therefore be
网络更深入，因此
able to form high order representations
能够形成高阶表示
of the data that was done by experts by
由专家完成的数据
human experts today networks are able to
今天人类专家网络 能够
do that that's the representation piece
那就是代表作品
and on top of the representation piece
并在代表作品的顶部
the final layers these networks are able
这些网络能够完成的最后一层
to accomplish the supervised learning
完成有监督的学习
tasks the generative tasks and the
任务生成任务和
unsupervised clustering tasks through
无监督的聚类任务
machine learning that's what we talked
机器学习这就是我们所说的
about a little in lecture one and we'll
在讲座 一 上课 ，我们会
continue tomorrow and Wednesday
明天和周三继续
that's supervised learning and you can
这是有监督的学习，你可以
think about the output of those networks
想想那些网络 的输出
as simple clean useful valuable
作为简单清洁有用的宝贵
information that's the knowledge and
信息 是 知识和
that knowledge can be in the form of
知识可以 是形式的
single numbers it could be regression
单个数字它可能是回归
continuous variables it could be a
连续变量可能是一个
sequence of numbers it can be images
它可以是图像的数字序列
audio sentences text speech once that
音频句子文本演讲一次
knowledge is extracted and aggregated
知识被提取和汇总
how do we connect it in multi resolution
我们如何以多分辨率连接它
always form hierarchies of ideas connect
总是形成思想层次结构的连接
ideas the trivial silly example is
想法是琐碎的愚蠢的例子
connecting images activity recognition
连接图像活动识别
and audio for example if it looks like a
和音频， 例如， 如果它看起来像
duck quacks like a duck and swims like a
鸭叫声像鸭子 ，游泳像
duck we do not currently have approaches
鸭我们目前没有办法
that effectively integrate this
有效地整合了这一点
information to produce a higher
信息，以 产生一个更高的
confidence estimate that is in fact the
信心估计实际上 是
duck and the planning piece the task of
鸭子和规划片的任务
taking the sensory information fusing
把感官信息融合起来
the sensory information and making
感官信息和制作
action control and longer-term plans
行动控制和长期计划
based on that information as we'll
根据我们的信息
discuss today
今天讨论
are more and more amenable to the
越来越顺从 了
learning approach to the deep learning
学习深度学习的方法
approach but to date have been the most
方法，但迄今为止最多
successful and non learning optimization
成功和非学习优化
based approaches like with the several
基于几种方法的基础方法
of the guest speakers we have including
我们 的演讲嘉宾 包括
the creator of this robot Atlas in
这个机器人 Atlas 的创造者
Boston Dynamics so the question how much
波士顿动力学所以问题多少
of the stack can be learned and to end
堆栈的结构可以 学习并结束
from the input to the output we know we
从 输入到输出我们都知道
can learn the representation and the
可以学习表示和
knowledge from the representation and to
来自代表和知识的知识
knowledge even with the kernel methods
知识即使使用内核方法
of SVM and certainly with with neural
SVM ，当然还有神经网络
networks mapping from representation to
网络从表示到映射
information has been where the primary
信息一直是主要的
success of machine learning over the
机器学习的成功飞越
past three decades has been mapping from
过去的三个十年里已经 从 映射
raw sensory data to knowledge that's
原始传感器数据到知识的
where the success the automated
自动化成功的地方
representation learning of deep learning
深度学习的表征学习
has been a success going straight from
直接取得了成功
raw data to knowledge the open question
原始数据 知识的开放性 问题
for us today and beyond is if we can
如果可以的话， 今天及 以后 对我们而言
expand the red box there of what can be
扩大红框那里什么都可以
learned and to end from sensory data to
从感官数据中学习并结束
reasoning so aggregating forming higher
推理如此聚合形成更高
representations of the extracted
提取的表示
knowledge and forming plans and acting
知识，形成计划和行动
in this world from the raw sensory data
在这个世界上从原始的感官数据
we will show the incredible fact that
我们将展示 令人难以置信的事实
we're able to do CERN exactly what's
我们能够做到CERN究竟是什么
shown here and to end with deeper
在这里显示并以更深的结尾
enforcement learning on trivial tasks in
执法学习琐碎的任务
a generalizable way the question is
一个普遍的问题是
whether that can then move on to
那是否可以继续
real-world tasks of autonomous vehicles
自动 驾驶汽车的现实任务
of humanoid robotics and so on that's
类人机器人等等
the open question so today let's talk
这个悬而未决的问题今天让我们谈谈吧
about reinforcement learning there's
关于加强学习 的问题
three types of machine learning
三种机器学习
supervised
监督
unsupervised are the categories at the
无监督是类别在
extremes in relative to the amount of
极端相 对于金额
human and human input that's required
需要的人和人的输入
for supervised learning every piece of
用于监督学习每一部分
data that's used for teaching these
用于教授这些数据的数据
systems is first labeled by human beings
系统首先 由人类标记
and unsupervised learning on the right
在右边无人监督学习
is no data is labeled by human beings in
没有数据是由人类标记
between is some sparse input from humans
之间是来自人类的一些稀疏输入
semi-supervised learning is when only
半监督学习是唯一的时
part of the data is provided by humans
部分数据由人类提供
ground truth and the rest must be
事实上，其余的必须是
inferred generalized by the system and
推断由系统推广和
that's what reinforcement learning Falls
那 是强化学习的结果
reinforcement learning has shown there
强化学习已经显示出来
with the cats as I said every successful
正如我所说的每一次成功的猫
presentation must include cats they're
演示必须包括他们的猫
supposed to be Pavlov's cats and ringing
应该是巴甫洛夫的猫和铃声
a bell and every time they ring a bell
一个铃铛，每次响铃
they're given food and they learn this
他们得到食物， 他们学到了 这一点
process the goal of reinforcement
处理 强化 的目标
learning is to learn from sparse reward
学习是从稀疏的 奖励中 学习
data from learn from sparse supervised
来自稀疏监督的数据
data and take advantage of the fact that
数据并利用这一事实
in simulation or in the real world there
在模拟中或在现实世界中
is a temporal consistency to the world
是世界的时间一致性
there is a temporal dynamics that
有一种时间动态
follows from state to state the state
从州到国家
through time and so you can propagate
通过时间，你可以 传播
information even if the information that
即使信息即信息
you're received about the the
你被收到了关于
supervision the ground truth is sparse
监督地面的事实是稀疏的
you can follow that information back
你 可以 回复那些信息
through time to infer something about
通过时间来推断 一些事情
the reality of what happened before then
在此 之前 发生的事实
even if your reward signals were weak so
即使你的奖励信号很弱也是如此
it's using the fact that the physical
它使用的是物理的事实
world evolves through time and some some
世界随着时间的推移和一些人而演变
sort of predictable way to take sparse
采取稀疏的可预测方式
information and generalize it over the
信息并将其推广到
entirety of the experience as being
完整的体验
learned so we apply this the two
我们学会了这两个
problems today we'll talk about deep
今天的问题我们会深入讨论
traffic as a methodology deep
交通作为一种方法深入
reinforcement learning so deep traffic
强化学习如此深入的交通
is a competition that we ran last year
是我们去年举办的比赛
and expanded significantly this year and
今年和今年显着扩大
I'll talk about some of the details and
我将讨论一些 细节和
how the folks in this room can on your
这个房间里的人怎么可以在你的房间里
smart phone today or if you have a
智能手机 今天或如果你有
laptop training agent while I'm talking
我正在 谈论笔记本电脑培训代理
training a neural network in the browser
在浏览器中训练神经网络
some of the things we've added our we've
我们已经添加了一些我们已经添加的东西
added the capability we've now turned it
增加了我们现在 转向它的能力
into a multi agent deeper enforcement
进入多代理更深层次的执法
learning problem where you can control
学习问题，你可以控制
up to ten cars within your network
您 网络中最多十辆汽车
perhaps less significant but pretty cool
也许不那么重要但非常酷
is the ability to customize the way the
是自定义方式的能力
agent looks so you can upload and people
代理看起来所以你可以上传和人
have to an absurd degree have already
已经荒谬了
begun doing so uploading different
开始这样做上传不同
images instead of the car that's shown
图像而不是显示的汽车
there as long as it maintains the
只要 它维持
dimensions shown here is a SpaceX rocket
这里显示的尺寸是SpaceX火箭
the competition is hosted on the website
比赛在网站上进行
self-driving cars that MIT ID you slash
麻省理工学院ID 自动驾驶的汽车
deep traffic will return to this later
深度流量将在稍后返回
the code is on github with some more
代码在github 上还有更多
information a starter code and a paper
信息 一个入门代码 和一篇论文
describing some of the fundamental
描述一些基本的
insights that will help you win at this
有助于您 在此 获胜的见解
competition is an archive
竞争是一种档案
so from supervised learning in lecture
所以从讲座中的监督学习
one to today supervised learning we can
一到今天我们可以监督学习
think of as memorization of ground truth
想到 记住 基本事实
data in order to form representations
为了形成表示数据
that generalizes from that ground truth
从那个基本事实 中推广 出来
reinforcement learning is we can think
强化学习是我们能想到的
of as a way to brute force propagate
作为暴力传播的一种方式
that information the sparse information
那些信息稀疏的信息
through time to to assign quality reward
通过时间来分配质量奖励
to state that does not directly have a
声明没有 直接的
reward to make sense of this world when
奖励，以了解这个世界的 时候
the rewards are sparse but are connected
奖励稀疏但是相互联系
through time you can think of that as
通过时间， 你可以把它想象成
reasoning so the
推理所以
through time is modeled in most
通过时间模拟大多数
reinforcement learning approaches very
强化学习非常接近
simply that there's an agent taking an
只是说有一个代理人 参加了
action in a state and receiving a little
在一个州采取行动并收到一点
reward and the agent operating in an
奖励和代理经营
environment execute an action receives
环境执行动作 接收
an observed state and new state and
观察到的状态和新状态
receives their reward this process
在 这个过程中得到奖励
continues over and over and some
一遍又一遍地继续
examples we can think of any of the
我们可以想到任何一个例子
video games some of which we'll talk
视频游戏，其中一些 我们会谈
about today like Atari breakout as the
今天 像雅达利突围 作为
environment the agent is the paddle each
环境中，代理人是 每个人的桨
action that the agent takes has an
代理人采取的行动有一个
influence on the evolution of the
影响人类的 进化
environment and the success is measured
环境和成功的衡量
by some reward mechanism in this case
在这种情况下通过一些奖励机制
points are given by the game and every
积分 由游戏和每个人给出
game has a different point scheme that
游戏有一个不同的点计划
must be converted normalized into a way
必须转换为规范化的方式
that's interpreted by the system and the
这是由系统解释 的
goal is to maximize those points
目标是 最大化这些点
maximize the reward the continuous
最大化奖励连续
problem of card pole by balancing the
卡杆的问题通过平衡
goal is to balance the pole on top of a
目标是平衡杆顶
moving cart the state is the angle the
移动车 状态是角度
angular speed the position of horizontal
角速度水平位置
velocity the actions are the horizontal
速度动作是水平的
force applied to the cart and the reward
力量应用于购物车 和奖励
is one at each time step if the pole is
如果杆是每个时间步是一个
still upright
还是挺直的
all the
一切
first-person shooters the video games is
视频游戏的第一人称射击游戏
now Starcraft the strategy games in case
现在Starcraft的战略游戏以防万一
of first-person shooter and doom what is
第一人称射击游戏 和 厄运是什么
the goal the environment is the game the
环境的目标是游戏
goal is to eliminate all opponents the
目标是消除所有对手
state is the raw game pixels coming in
状态是进入的原始游戏像素
the actions is moving up down left right
行动向左上方向上移动
and so on and the reward is positive
等等，奖励是积极的
when eliminating an opponent and
当消灭对手和
negative when the agent is eliminated
当代理被淘汰时为负
industrial robotics been packin with a
工业机器人一直在用
robotic arm the goal is to pick up a
机器人手臂 的目标是 拿起 一个
device from a box and put it into a
装置从一个盒子里把 它放进去
container the state is the raw pixels of
容器状态是 原始像素
the real world that the robot observes
机器人观察的现实世界
the actions are the possible actions of
行动是可能的行动
the robot the different degrees of
机器人上的不同程度 的
freedom are moving through those degrees
自由正在 通过这些程度
moving the different actuators to
将不同的执行器移动到
realize of the position of the arm and
意识到手臂和手臂的位置
the reward is positive when placing a
放置 时奖励是正
device successfully and negative
设备成功和否定
otherwise everything could be modeled in
否则一切都 可以建模
this way Markov decision process there's
这种方式马尔可夫的决策过程就在那里
a state as zero action a zero and reward
零状态为零 和奖励的状态
received a new state is achieved again
收到新状态再次实现
action rewards state action rewards
行动奖励国家行动奖励
state until a terminal state is reached
状态，直到达到终端状态
and the major components of
和。的主要组成部分
reinforcement learning is a policy some
强化学习是一种政策
kind of plan of what to do in every
那种 在每一个做 什么计划
single state what kind of action to
单身状态 是什么样的动作
perform a value function a some kind of
执行某种值函数
sense of what is a good state to be in
什么是 好状态的感觉
of what is a good action to take in a
什么是一个很好的行动 ，采取在
state and sometimes a model that the
状态， 有时一个模型 ，它的
agent represents the environment with
agent代表环境
some kind of sense of the environment
某种 环境 意识
its operating in the dynamics of that
其在该动态操作
environment that's useful for making
对制作 有用的环境
decisions about actions let's take a
关于行动的决定让我们采取行动
trivial example
琐碎的例子
a grid world of three by four twelve
一个 三乘 四十二 的网格世界
squares we start at the bottom left and
我们开始在左下角 广场
their task with walking about this world
他们走遍这个世界的任务
to maximize reward they're awarded at
最大限度地奖励他们获得的奖励
the top right is a plus 1 and a 1 square
右上角是 加 1和1平方
below that is a negative 1 and every
下面是负1和 每个
step you take is a punishment or is a
你采取的步骤是惩罚或是一个
negative reward of 0.04 so what is the
负面奖励0.04那么是什么
optimal policy in this world now when
现在这个世界上的最佳政策
everything is deterministic perhaps this
一切都是确定性的也许这个
is the policy when you start the bottom
当你开始触底时是政策
left well because every step hurts every
离开很好，因为每一步都伤害了每一个
step has a negative reward
步骤有负面的 回报
then you want to take the shortest path
那么你想走最短的路
to the maximum square with a maximum
到最大正方形最大值
reward when the state space is
奖励时态空间
non-deterministic as presented before
如前所述的非确定性
with a probability of 0.8 when you
当你 的概率为 0.8
choose to go up you go up but with
选择上升你 上去 但是
probability 0.1 you go left and point 1
概率为0.1你离开并指向1
you go right unfair again much like life
你再次变得不公平，就像生活一样
that would be the optimal policy what is
这将是最优政策
the Keith observation here that every
基思在这里观察到的每一个
single state in the space must have a
空间中的 单一状态 必须具有
plan because you can't because then a
计划，因为你 不能因为那么一个
non-deterministic aspect of the control
控制的非确定性方面
you can't control where you're going to
你无法控制你去哪里
end up so you must have a plan for every
结束所以你必须为每个人制定计划
place that's the policy having an action
这是政策有行动的地方
an optimal action to take in every
最佳的行动， 采取在每
single state now suppose we change the
单身现在假设我们改变了
reward structure and for every step we
奖励结构和我们的每一步
take there's a negative reward is a
拿一个负面的 奖励 是一个
negative 2 so it really hurts there's a
负2所以真的很痛苦 有一个
high punishment for every single step we
我们每一步都要受到高度惩罚
take so no matter what we always take
无论我们 总是采取 什么措施，这样 做
the shortest path the optimal policy is
最优政策的最短路径
to take the shortest path to the to the
走最短路径去
only spot on the board that doesn't
只有在没有的板上
result in punishment if we decrease the
如果我们减少 了， 就会导致惩罚
reward of each step to negative 0.1 the
奖励每一步到负0.1
policy changes whether
政策变化是否
some extra degree of wandering
一些额外的徘徊程度
encouraged and as we go further and
鼓励，随着我们走得更远
further in lowering the punishment as
进一步 降低 惩罚作为
before to negative 0.04 more wandering
之前以负0.04 多徘徊
and more wandering is allowed and when
允许更多的游荡和什么时候
we finally turn the reward into positive
我们终于将 奖励 转为积极的
so every step it every step is increases
所以每走一步都会增加
the reward then there's a significant
奖励然后有一个重要的
incentive to to stay on the board
鼓励留在董事会
without ever reaching the destination
没有到达目的地
kind of like college for a lot of people
有点像很多人的大学
so the value function the way we think
所以价值就像我们思考的那样发挥作用
about the value of a state or the value
关于 国家或价值的价值
of anything in the environment is the
在环境中任何事物是
reward were likely to receive in the
奖励有可能 获得在
future and the way we see the reward
未来和 我们看待奖励的方式
were likely to receive as we discount
很可能会收到我们的折扣
the future award because we can't always
未来的奖项因为我们不能永远
count on it
指望它
here Gama further and further out into
Gama越走越远 了
the future more and more discounts
未来 越来越 多的折扣
decreases the reward the importance of
减少奖励的重要性
the reward received and the good
收到的奖励和好处
strategy is taking the sum of these
战略正在考虑这些的总和
rewards and maximizing it maximizing the
奖励和最大化它最大化
scoundrel ward
歹徒病房
that's what reinforcement learning hopes
这就是强化学习所希望的
to achieve and with cue learning we use
实现和 我们使用的提示学习
any policy to estimate the value of
任何估算价值的政策
taking an action in a state so off
在这样一个州采取行动
policy forget policy we move about the
政策忘记我们的政策
world and use the bellman equation here
世界并 在这里使用贝尔曼方程
on the bottom to continuously update our
在底部不断更新 我们的
estimate of how good a certain action is
估计某项 行动的 好坏程度
in a certain state so we don't need this
在某种状态，所以我们不需要这个
this allows us to operate in a much
这使我们 能够在很多方面运作
larger state space in a much larger
更大的国家空间更大
action space we move about this world
行动空间我们 在这个世界上 移动
through simulation or in the real world
通过模拟或在现实世界中
taking actions and updating our estimate
采取行动并更新我们的估计
of how good certain actions are over
某些行动有多好
I'm the new state at the left is the is
我是左边的新州 是
the updated value the old state is the
旧 状态的更新值
starting value for the equation and we
等式的起始值和我们
update that old state estimation with
更新 旧的状态估计
the sum of the reward received by taking
服用 奖励的总和
action s tax action a and state us and
行动的税收行动a并 声明我们和
the maximum reward that's possible to be
可能的最大奖励
received in the following states
收到以下州
discounted that update is decreased with
折扣更新 减少了
a learning rate the higher the learning
学习率越高，学习越高
rate the more value we the the faster
我们越快，价值就越高
will learn the more value we assigned to
将学习 我们赋予的更多价值
new information that's simple that's it
新的信息很 简单 就是这样
that's Q learning the simple update rule
那是Q 学习 简单的更新规则
allows us to to explore the world and as
让我们探索世界和
we explore get more and more information
我们探索获取越来越多的信息
about what's good to do in this world
关于在这个世界上做什么好事
and there's always a balance in the
而且也总是 在 平衡
various problem spaces we'll discuss
我们将讨论各种问题空间
there's always a balance between
总之间有平衡
exploration and exploitation as you form
你形成的探索和利用
a better and better estimate of the Q
对 Q的更好和更好的估计
function of what actions are good to
什么行动 的好处
take you start to get a sense of what is
带你开始了解 它是什么
the best action to take but it's not a
采取的最佳行动，但不是
perfect sense it's still an
完美的感觉它仍然是一个
approximation and so there's value of
近似值， 因此有价值
exploration but the better and better
探索但 越来越好
your estimate becomes the less and less
你的估计变得越来越少了
exploration has a benefit so usually we
探索有利于 我们
want to explore a lot in the beginning
想在一开始就探索很多
and less and less so towards the end and
并且越来越少到 最后
when we finally release the system out
当我们最终释放出系统 时
into the world and wish it to operate
进入世界并希望它运作
its best then we have it operate as a
最好的， 然后我们把它作为一个
greedy system always taking the optimal
贪婪系统始终采取最佳
action according to the q2 key value
根据 q2键值进行操作
function and everything I'm talking
功能和 我正在谈论的 一切
about now is permit rised and our
现在是许可证上升 和我们的
parameters that are very important for
这是 非常重要的参数
winning the deep traffic competition
赢得了深度交通竞争
which is using this very algorithm with
这是使用这个非常算法
a neural network at its core so for sin
一个神经网络的核心，所以罪恶
table representation of a cue function
的 提示功能 的表表示
where the y-axis is state four states s
其中，y轴是状态4个状态 s
one two three four and the x-axis is
一二三四， x轴是
actions a one two three four we can
行动一两三 四我们可以
think of this table as randomly
把这个表当作随机的
initiated or initiated initialized in
启动或启动初始化
any kind of way that's not
任何一种不是这样的方式
representative of actual reality and as
代表实际 的 现实和
we move about this world and we take
我们走动这个世界 ，我们采取
actions we update this table with the
我们使用的更新此表的操作
bellman equation shown up top and here
贝尔曼方程显示在顶部和这里
slides now are online you can see a
幻灯片现在 在网上可以 看到
simple pseudocode algorithm of how to
简单伪码算法如何
update it how to run this bellman
更新它如何运行这个门卫
equation and over time the approximation
方程式和随着时间的推移近似
becomes the optimal cue table
成为最佳提示表
the problem is when that cue table it
问题是那个cue表吧
becomes exponential in size when we take
当我们采取时，变成指数大小
in raw sensory information as we do with
像我们一样处理原始的感官信息
cameras with deep crash or with deep
深度撞击或深度撞击的相机
traffic it's taking the full grid space
它占据了整个网格空间
and taking that information the raw the
并把这些信息原始的
raw grid pixels of deep traffic and when
原始网格像素的深度流量和时间
you take the arcade games here they're
你在这里参加街机游戏
taking the raw pixels of the game or
拍摄游戏的原始像素或
when we take go the game of go when it's
当我们开始游戏的时候
taking the units the the board the raw
将单位作为原始单位
state of the board as the input the
董事会的状态作为输入
potential state space the number of
潜在的状态空间的数量
possible combinations of what states it
什么 陈述的可能组合
possible is extremely large larger than
可能是非常大的比
we can certainly hold the memory and
我们当然可以保持 记忆
larger that we can ever be able to
较大，我们可以永远能够
accurately approximate through the
准确地 通过近似
bellman equation over time through
贝尔曼方程随着 时间的推移
simulation through the simple update of
通过简单的更新模拟
the bellman equation so this is where
贝尔曼方程所以这就是这里
deep reinforcement learning comes in
深入的强化学习进来了
neural networks are really good
神经网络非常好
approximate errs they're really good at
近似于他们真正擅长的人
exactly this task of learning this kind
正是这种学习这种任务的任务
of cue table
提示表
so as we started with supervised
所以我们从监督开始
learning or neural networks helped us
学习或神经网络 帮助了我们
memorize patterns using supervised
使用监督记忆模式
ground true data and we'll move to
真实的数据，我们将转向
reinforcement learning that hopes to
强化学习是希望
propagate outcomes to knowledge deep
将结果传播到知识深处
learning allows us to do so on much
学习使我们能够做到这一点
larger state spaces are much larger
较大的状态空间要大得多
action spaces which means it's
动作空间意味着它
generalizable it's much more capable to
可推广它更有能力
deal with the raw stuff of sensory data
处理感官数据的原始内容
which means it's much more capable to
这意味着它更有能力
deal with the broad variation of real
处理真实的广泛变化
world applications and it does so
世界应用程序，它就是这样
because it's able to learn the
因为它能够学习
representations as we discussed on
我们讨论过的陈述
Monday the understanding comes from
周一理解来自
converting the raw sensory information
转换原始感官信息
into into simple useful information
进入简单有用的信息
based on which the action in this
根据其中的行动
particular state can be taken in the
特殊的国家可以采取
same exact way so instead of the cue
同样的确切方式，而不是 提示
table instead of this cue function we
表而不是这个 cue函数我们
plug in a neural network where the input
插入神经网络输入的地方
is the state space no matter how complex
无论多么复杂，都是国家空间
and the output is a value for each of
并且输出是每个 的 值
the actions that you could take input is
你可以采取的行动是
the state output is the value of the
状态输出是的值
function it's simple this is deep Q
功能很简单，这 是 深Q
Network DQ one at the core of the
网络 DQ一个核心
success of deep mind a lot of the cool
深刻的心灵成功很多 很酷
stuff you see about video games D
你看到的关于视频游戏的东西 D.
queuing or variants of DQ and our play
排队或DQ和我们的游戏的变种
this is water first with a nature paper
这是 水首先用自然 纸
a deep mind the success came of playing
一个深刻的 思想成功来自于玩
the different games including Atari
包括Atari在内的不同游戏
games
游戏
how are these things trained very
这些 东西怎么训练得很好
similar to supervised learning the
类似于监督学习
bellman equation up top
贝尔曼方程式顶部
it takes the reward and the discounted
它采用奖励和折扣
expected reward from future states the
来自未来国家的预期奖励
loss function here for neural network
神经网络的损失函数
and you'll now work learners with a loss
而你现在会让学习者失去理智
function it takes the reward received at
功能它需要收到的奖励
the current state does a forward pass
目前的状态是向前传球
through a neural network to estimate the
通过神经网络 来估计
value of the future state of the best
未来最佳状态的 价值
action to take in the future state and
采取行动以 应对未来的国家和地区
then subtract that from the forward pass
然后从前 向传球中减去
through the network for the current
通过网络为当前
state in action so you take the
行动中的状态，所以你采取了
difference between what your a Q
你的Q 之间的区别
estimator
估计
then you'll network believes the value
然后你会 网络相信价值
of the current state is and what it more
当前状态是什么以及更多
likely is to be based on the value of
很可能是基于 价值
the future states that are reachable
可以到达的未来状态
based on the actions you can take here's
基于你可以采取的行动
the algorithm input is the state output
算法输入是状态输出
is the Q value for each action or in
是每个动作或的动作的Q值
this diagram input is the state in
此图输入是状态
action and the output is the Q value
动作和输出是Q值
it's very similar architectures so given
这是非常相似的架构
a transition of s a are s prime s
sa的过渡是 最重要的
current state taking an action receiving
当前状态采取行动接收
reward and achieving US prime state the
奖励和实现美国黄金州
the update is to a feed-forward pass
更新是前馈 传递
through the network for the current
通过网络为当前
state do a feed-forward pass for each of
国家为每个人做一个前馈传球
the possible actions taken in the next
下一步可能采取的行动
state and that's how we compute the two
状态，这就是我们如何计算这两者
parts of the loss function and update
部分损失功能 和更新
the weights using back propagation again
再次使用反向传播的权重
loss function back propagation is how
损失函数反向传播是如何
the network is trained this has actually
实际上 ，网络是训练有素的
been around for much longer than the
出现 了 比长得 多
deep mind a few tricks made it made it
深刻的思想 使它成功 了
really work experience replays the
真正的工作经验重播
biggest one so as the games are played
这是游戏中最大的一个
through simulation or if it's a physical
通过模拟或如果它是物理的
system as it acts in the world it's
系统，因为它在世界 上行动
actually collecting the observations
实际收集观察结果
into a library of experiences and that
进入一个经验库和 那个
training is performed by randomly
训练是随机进行的
sampling the library in the past by
通过采样库在过去
randomly sampling the previous
随机抽样前一个
experiences and batches so you're not
经验和批次所以你不是
always training on the natural
总是训练自然
continuous evolution of the system
系统的不断发展
you're training on randomly picked
你是随机挑选的训练
batches of those experiences that's like
批次的那些经历就像
huge it's a it's a seems like a subtle
巨大的它是一个看起来像一个微妙的
trick but it's a really important one so
伎俩，但它是一个非常重要的 一个，这样
the system doesn't over fit a particular
系统不适合 特定的
evolution of this of the game of the
这个游戏的演变
simulation another important again
模拟另一个重要的
subtle trick as in a lot of deep
很多深刻的微妙技巧
learning approaches the subtle tricks
学习接近微妙的技巧
make all the difference is fixing the
让所有不同的是修复
target network for the loss function if
目标网络的损失函数if
you notice you have to use the neural
你注意到你 必须使用 神经
network thick the singly neural network
网络厚的单神经网络
the gqi network to estimate the value of
所述GQI网络估计的值
the current state and action pair and
当前的状态 和 行动对和
next so using it multiple times and as
下一因此 使用它多次 和
you perform that operation you're
你执行那项操作
updating the network which means the
更新网络意味着
target function inside that loss
失败中的 目标函数
function is always changing so you're
功能总是在变化 所以你是
the very nature your loss function is
你的损失功能的本质
changing all the time as you're learning
在你 学习的过程中不断变化
and that's a big problem for stability
这 对稳定性 来说是个大问题
that can create big problems for the
可以创建 的 大问题
learning process so this little trick is
学习过程所以这个小技巧是
to fix the network and only update it
修复网络，只更新它
every safe thousand steps so as you
每个安全的千 步，所以你
train the network the the network that's
训练网络 是这样的 网络
used to compute the target function
用于计算 目标函数
inside the loss function is fixed it
里面的损失函数是固定的
produces a more stable computation on a
在a上产生更稳定的计算
loss function so the ground doesn't
损失功能所以地面没有
shift under you as you're trying to find
当你想要找到时，在你身下转移
a minimal for the loss function the loss
损失函数的最小损失
function doesn't change in unpredictable
功能不会在不可预测的情况下改变
difficult to understand ways and reward
难以理解的方式和奖励
clipping which is always true with
剪裁它总是与 真实
general systems that are operating it's
正在运行它的一般系统
seeking to operate in the generalized
寻求在广义上运作
way is for very for these various games
方式是非常适合这些各种游戏
the points are different some some
一些人的观点不同
points are low some points are high some
分数很低，有些分数很高
go positive and negative and they're all
积极 和消极，他们都是
normalized to a point where the good
归一化为好的点
points or the positive points are a 1
积分或积分是1
and negative points are a negative 1
和负点是负 1
that's reward clipping simplify the
那个奖励剪辑简化了
reward structure and because a lot of
奖励结构，因为很多
the games are 30 FPS or 60 FPS and the
比赛是30 FPS或60 FPS 和
actions are not it's not valuable to
行动不是没有价值的
take actions at such a high rate inside
在 里面 以如此高的 速度 采取行动
of these as particularly Atari games
其中特别是Atari游戏
then you only take an action every four
那么你每四个只采取一次行动
steps while still taking in the frames
步骤，同时仍然采取框架
as part of the temporal window to make
作为时间窗口的一部分
decisions tricks but hopefully gives you
决定技巧但希望能给你
a sense of the kind of things necessary
一种必要的事物感
for both seminal papers like this one
对于像这样的两篇开创性论文
and for the more important
而对于更重要的
accomplishment of winning deep traffic
赢得深度交通的成就
is that
就是它
the tricks make all the difference here
这些技巧在这里有所不同
on the bottom is the circle is when the
在底部是圆圈的时候
technique is used in the x1 it's not
技术在x1中使用它不是
looking at replay and target takes
看重播和目标需要
target network and experience replay
目标网络和 体验重播
when both are used for the game of
当两者都用于游戏时
breakout River raid sea quests and Space
突围河突袭海上任务和空间
Invaders
侵略者
the higher the number the better it is
数字越高越好
the more points achieved so when it
更多 的积分达到 ，所以当 它
gives you a sense that when replay and
让你感觉到重播和
target both gives significant
目标都有重要意义
improvements in the performance of the
改善了表现
system order of magnitude improvements
系统数量级的改进
two orders of magnitude for breakup and
两个数量级的 解体和
here is pseudocode of implementing dq1
这是实现 dq1的伪代码
the learning the key thing to notice and
学习关键的事情要注意和
you can look to the slides is the the
你可以看一下幻灯片 是 的
loop the while loop of playing through
循环播放的while循环
the games and selecting the actions to
游戏和选择行动
play is not part of the training it's
游戏不是训练的一部分
it's part of the saving the observations
这是保存观察的一部分
the state action reward next state
国家行动 奖励 下一个州
observation is saving them into replay
观察是将它们保存 为重播
memory into that library and then you
记忆到那个库 然后你
sample randomly from that replay memory
从该重放内存中随机抽样
to then train the network based on the
然后根据网络训练网络
loss function and with probability up up
损失函数和概率上升
top with the probability epsilon select
顶部有概率 epsilon选择
a random action that epsilon is the
epsilon的随机动作
probability of exploration that
探索的概率
decreases that's something you'll see in
减少那些你会看到的东西
deep traffic as well is the rate at
深交通以及处于率
which that exploration decreases over
那次探索减少了
time through the training process you
通过培训过程的时间你
want to explore a lot first and less and
想先探索一下 ，少 探索一下
less over time so this algorithm is
少随着时间的推移所以这种 算法
being able to accomplish in 2015 and
能够在2015年完成 ，并
since a lot of incredible things things
因为很多 不可思议的事情的东西
that made the AI world think that we
这让AI世界认为我们
were onto something that
人到 的东西，
general AI is within reach for the first
一般AI是第一个可达到的
time that raw sensor information was
原始传感器信息的时间
used to create a system that acts and
用于创建一个行为和
makes sense of the world make sense of
让世界 变得 有意义
the physics of the world enough to be
世界的物理学就足够了
able to succeed in it from very little
能够从很小的角度取得成功
information but these games are trivial
信息， 但 这些游戏 是 微不足道的
even though there is a lot of them this
即使他们中有很多这个
dqn approach has been able to outperform
dqn方法已经 超越了
a lot of the Atari games
很多Atari游戏
that's what's been reported on
这就是报道的 内容
outperform the human level performance
超越人类的表现
but again these games are trivial what I
但是这些游戏 对我而言 都是微不足道的
think and perhaps biased I'm biased but
思考，也许有偏见我有偏见 但是
one of the greatest accomplishments of
最伟大的成就之一
artificial intelligence in the last
人工智能 在最后
decade at least from the philosophical
十年至少从 哲学角度 来看
or the research perspective is alphago 0
或者研究视角是alphago 0
first alphago and then alphago 0 its
首先是alphago， 然后是alphago 0
deepmind system that beat the best in
深度 打击最好的 系统
the world in a game of go so what's the
在这场比赛 中的世界是 如此
game of go it's simple I won't get into
去 它的游戏很简单，我不会进入
the rules but basically it's a 19 by 19
规则，但基本上它是一个19乘19
board shown on the bottom of the slide
幻灯片底部显示的板
for the bottom row of the table for a
为表 的 最下面一行
board of 19 by 19 the number of legal
董事会19人19人的合法人数
game positions is 2 times 10 to the
比赛位置 是10倍的10倍
power of 170 it's a very large number of
170的力量是一个非常大的 数字
possible positions to consider any one
可能的立场考虑任何一个
time especially the game evolves the
时间特别是游戏 进化了
number of possible moves is huge much
可能的动作数量非常多
larger than in chess so that's why AI
比国际象棋更大，这就是人工智能的原因
the community thought that this game is
社区认为这个游戏是
not solvable until 2016 when alphago
直到2016年alphago时才能解决
used this use human expert position play
使用这个使用人类专家的位置发挥
to seed in a supervised way
以有监督的方式种子
reinforcement learning approach and I'll
强化学习方法，我会
describe in a little bit of detail and a
用一点点细节描述 一下
couple of slides here
几个 幻灯片 在这里
to beat the best in the world and then
然后打败世界上 最好 的
alphago 0 that is the accomplishment of
alphago 0即 成就
the decade for me in AI is being able to
人工智能的十年是能够的
play with no training data on human
没有关于人类的训练数据
expert games and beat the best in the
专家游戏并击败了最好的
world in an extremely complex game this
这是一场极其复杂的比赛
is not Atari this is and this is a much
这不是Atari，这 是一个很大的问题
higher order difficulty game and that
高阶难度游戏和那个
and the quality of players that is
和玩家的素质是
competing in is much higher and it's
竞争对手要高得多
able to extremely quickly here to
能够非常迅速地到这里来
achieve a rating that's better than
达到更好的评级
alphago and better than the different
alphago 和优于 不同的
variants of alphago and certainly better
alphago的变种， 当然更好
than the best of the human players in 21
比21中 最好 的 人类球员
days of self play so how does it work
自我玩耍的日子，它是如何运作的
all of these approaches much much like
所有这些方法非常类似
the previous ones the traditional ones
以前的传统的
that are not based on deep learning are
不是基于深度 学习的
using Monte Carlo tree search MCTS
使用蒙特卡罗树 搜索 MCTS
which is when you have such a large
那是你有这么大的时候
state space you start at a board and you
你从董事会 和 你开始的国家空间
play and you choose moves with some
玩，你 选择一些动作
exploitation exploration balancing
开发探索平衡
choosing to explore totally new
选择全新探索
positions or to go deep in the positions
职位或深入职位
you know are good until the bottom of
你知道直到底部都很好
the game is reached until the final
到达比赛直到最后
state is reached and then you back
到达状态，然后你回来
propagate the quality of the choices you
宣传您的选择质量
made leading to that position
导致这个位置
and in that way you learn the value of
并以这种方式你学习的价值
of board positions and play that's been
董事会职位和比赛的情况
used by the most successful go playing
用于最成功的去玩
engines before and alphago since but you
之前的引擎和alphago ，但是你
might be able to guess what's the
也许可以 猜测有什么
difference with alphago verse to the
与alphago 诗歌的区别
previous approaches they use the neural
以前的方法他们使用神经
network
网络
as the intuition quote-unquote - what
作为直觉引用 - 不 引用 - 什么
are the good states what are the good
好的状态 是好的
next board positions to explore and the
下一个董事会的位置，以探索和
key things again the tricks make all the
关键的事情再次 伎俩让所有的
difference that made alphago zero work
使 alphago无效的差异
and work much better than alphago is
并且工作比alphago好多了
first because there was no expert play
首先是因为没有专家比赛
instead of human games
而不是人类游戏
alphago used that very same Monte Carlo
alphago 使用了 同样的蒙特卡罗
tree search algorithm MCTS to do an
树搜索算法 MCTS做了一个
intelligent look ahead based on the
智能前瞻基于
neural network prediction of where dove
神经网络预测鸽子的位置
the good States to take it checked that
好的国家接受它检查
instead of human expert play it checked
而不是人类专家发挥它检查
how good indeed are those states it's a
这些国家确实有多好
simple look ahead action that does the
简单的预见行动，做到了
ground truth that does the target
实现目标的基本事实
correction that produces the loss
产生损失的修正
function the second part is the
功能第二部分是
multitask learning what's now called
多任务学习现在称之为什么
multitask learning is the networkers is
多任务学习是网络工作者
quote-unquote two-headed in the sense
从某种意义上来说， 引用 - 不引用 双头
that first it outputs the probability of
首先它输出概率
which move to take the obvious thing and
采取明显的事情和移动
it's also producing a probability of
它也产生了概率
winning and there's a few ways to
获奖并有一些方法 来
combine that information and
结合这些信息和
continuously train both parts of the
不断培养的两个部分
network depending on the choice taken so
网络取决于 所采取的选择
you want to take the best choice in the
你想在这里做出最好的选择
short term and achieve the positions
短期并实现立场
that are highly a slightly hood of
这是一个非常轻微的引擎盖
winning for the player that's whose turn
赢得了轮到谁 的球员
it is and another big step is that they
它是另一个重要的一步就是他们
updated from 2015 the updated of the
从2015年更新了 最新的
state-of-the-art architecture which are
最先进的 建筑
now the architecture that one imagenet
现在是一个 imagenet 的架构
as the residual networks ResNet for
作为残差网络 RESNET 为
imagenet those that's it
imagenet那就是它
and those little changes made all the
而那些微小的变化使所有人
difference so that takes us to deep
差异使我们 带到 深
traffic and the eight billion hours
交通和 八十亿小时
stuck in traffic
堵在路上
America's pastime so we tried to
美国的消遣， 所以我们试图
simulate driving that behavior layer of
模拟驾驶那个行为层
driving so not the immediate control not
驾驶所以不是直接控制不是
the motion planning but beyond that on
运动规划，但超越 了
top on top of those control decisions
在 这些控制决策 之上
the human interpretable decisions of
人类可解释的决定
changing lane of speeding up slowing
改变加速减速的车道
down modeling that in a micro traffic
在微流量中建模
simulation framework that's popular in
在中国流行的模拟框架
traffic engineering the kind of shown
交通工程所示的那种
here we apply deep reinforcement
在这里我们应用深层加固
learning to that I'll call it deep
学习， 我会称之为 深刻
traffic the goal is to achieve the
交通的目标是 实现 目标
highest average speed over a long period
长期 最高的 平均速度
of time weaving in and out of traffic
时间编织进出交通
for students here the requirement is to
这里学生的要求是
follow the tutorial and achieve a speed
按照教程并达到速度
of 65 miles an hour and if you really
每小时65英里，如果你真的
want to achieve a speed over 70 miles an
希望达到超过70英里的速度
hour which is what's acquired to win and
小时，这是 赢得和获得的
perhaps upload your own image to make
也许是上传自己的图片 ，使
sure you look good doing it what you
确定你看起来很好，做到了你
should do clear instructions to compete
应该做清楚的竞争指示
read the tutorial you can change
阅读您 可以更改的教程
parameters in the code box on that
在该代码框中参数
website cars done on mighty dad you size
网站汽车完成 你的大小强大的爸爸
deep traffic click the white button that
深度流量点击白色按钮
says apply code which applies the code
说应用代码应用代码
that you write these are the parameters
你写这些是参数
that you specify then you'll network it
您指定 的 ，那么你就网络信息技术
applies those parameters creates the
应用那些参数创建
architecture do you specify and now you
你指定的架构，现在你
have a network written in JavaScript
有一个用JavaScript编写的网络
living in the browser ready to be
生活在浏览器中准备好了
trained then you click the blue button
训练然后你点击蓝色 按钮
that says run training and that trains
那说 训练和训练
the network much faster than one's
网络比 一个人 快得多
actually being visualized in the browser
实际上是在浏览器中可视化
a thousand times faster by evolving the
通过 不断发展的 快 1000 倍
game making decisions taking in the grid
游戏制作决策参与网格
space as I'll talk about here in a
我将在 这里谈论空间
second the speed limit is 80 miles an
第二，限速是80英里
hour based on the various adjustments
小时根据各种调整
were made to the game reaching 80 miles
这场比赛 达到了80英里
an hour is certainly impossible an
一个小时肯定是不可能的
average and reaching some of the speeds
平均并达到一些速度
that we've achieved last year
我们去年取得的成就
it's much much much more difficult
这要困难得多
finally when you're happy and the
终于，当你快乐 的时候
training is done submit the model to
培训完成后 提交 模型
competition for those super eager
竞争那些超级渴望的人
dedicated students you can do so every
敬业的学生， 你可以做到每一个
five minutes and to visualize your
五分钟， 并想象 你的
submission you can click the request
提交您可以 单击该请求
visualization specifying the custom
可视化指定自定义
image and the color okay
图像和颜色没关系
so here's the simulation speed limit 80
所以这是模拟速度限制 80
miles an hour
一小时一英里
cars 20 on the screen one of them is a
屏幕上的汽车20其中一个 是
red one in this case that's that one is
在这种情况下，红色的是那个
controlled by a neural network its speed
由 神经网络控制其速度
it's allowed the actions of speed up
它允许加速的行动
slow down change lanes left-right or
减慢变化车道 左右或
stay exactly the same the other cars are
和其他车完全一样
pretty dumb they speed up slow down turn
相当愚蠢， 他们加速减速转弯
left right but they don't have a purpose
向左， 但他们没有目的
in their existence they do so randomly
在他们的存在中 他们是随机的
or at least purpose has not been
或者至少目的还没有
discovered the road the car the speed
发现了汽车的速度之路
the road is a grid space an occupancy
这条路是 一个占用 的网格空间
grid that specifies when it's empty
指定何时为空的网格
it's set to a B meaning that the the
它被设置为B意味着
grid value is whatever speed is
网格值是什么速度
achievable if you were inside that grid
如果你 在那个 网格 里面就可以实现
and when there's other cars that are
当有其他汽车的时候
going slow the value in that grid is the
这个网格中的值变慢了
speed of that car that's the state space
这辆车的速度就是国家空间
that's the state representation and you
这是国家代表和你
can choose how much what slice that
可以选择多少切片
state space you take in that's the input
你接受的状态空间就是 输入
to the neural network for a visual
到神经网络的 视觉
Asian purposes you can choose normal
亚洲目的你可以选择 正常
speed or fast speed for watching the
观看速度或速度快
network operate and there's display
网络运行，并有显示
options to help you build intuition
帮助您建立直觉的选项
about the network takes in and what
关于网络发生在什么
space that car is operating in the
空间车在运行
default is no extra information is added
默认是没有添加额外信息
then there's the learning input which
再有就是学习用输入 其
visualizes exactly which part of the
准确地想象出哪个部分
road the is serves as the input to the
道路是作为输入
network then there is the safety system
网络然后有 安全系统
which I'll describe in a little bit
我将在 一点点 描述
which is all the parts of the road the
这是道路的所有部分
car is not allowed to go into because it
汽车是不允许 进入的，因为它
would result in a collision and that
会导致碰撞
with JavaScript would be very difficult
使用JavaScript会非常困难
to animate and the full map here's a
动画和完整的地图这里是一个
safety system you could think of this
安全系统， 你可以 想到这一点
system as a CC basic radar ultrasonic
系统作为 CC基本雷达超声
sensors helping you avoid the obvious
传感器帮助您避免明显的
collisions to obviously detectable
碰撞到 明显检测
objects around you and the task for this
你周围的物体和它 的 任务
red car for the steel Network is to move
钢网的红色车是移动
about this space is to move about the
这个空间是 将 有关
space under the constraints of the
在约束下的空间
safety system the red shows all the
安全系统 红色显示所有
parts of the grid it's not able to move
网格的部件是无法 移动
into so the goal for the car is to not
因此， 汽车 的目标 是不
get stuck in traffic it's make big
陷入交通堵塞它变大了
sweeping motions to avoid crowds of cars
清扫运动，以避免汽车的人群
the input like DQ n is the state space
像DQ n这样的输入是状态空间
the output is the value of the different
输出是不同的值
actions and based on the epsilon
行动并基于epsilon
parameter through training and through
参数通过培训和通过
inference evaluation process you choose
您选择的推理评估过程
how much exploration you want to do
你想做多少探索
these are all parameters the learning is
这些都是学习的参数
done in the browser on your own computer
在 您 自己的计算机 上的浏览器中完成
utilizing only the CPU the action space
仅利用CPU的动作空间
there's five giving you some of the
有五个给你一些
variables here perhaps you go back to
这里的变量也许你会回去
the slides to look at it the brain quote
幻灯片来 看看它的大脑报价
unquote is the thing that takes in the
unquote 是接受的东西
state and the reward takes a four
国家和奖励需要四个
passed through the state and produce to
通过 国家 并生产 到
the next action the brain is where the
大脑的下一步行动在哪里
neural network is contained both of the
神经网络包含两者
training and the evaluation the learning
培训和评估 学习
input can be controlled in width forward
输入可以向前控制​​宽度
length and backward length lane side
长度和后退长度 车道侧
number of lanes to the side that you see
你看到的 那条 车道的数量
patches ahead as the patches ahead that
前面的补丁作为前面的补丁
you see patches behind as patches behind
你看到补丁背后的补丁
the you see mu this year can control the
你看到mu 今年可以控制了
number of agents that are controlled by
受控制 的代理数量
the neural network anywhere from one to
神经网络从一个到另一个
ten and the evaluation is performed
十是 进行 评价
exactly the same way you have to achieve
完全一样， 你必须达到
the highest average speed for the agents
最高平均速度为 代理商
the very critical thing here is the
这里非常关键的是
agents are not aware of each other so
代理人不知道对方如此
they're not jointly jointly planning the
他们没有联合策划
network is trained under the joint
网络是在联合下训练的
objective of achieving the average speed
达到平均速度的目标
for all of them
对于 他们所有人
but the actions are taking in a greedy
但行动贪婪
way for each it's very interesting what
每一路这是非常有趣的东西
can be learned in this way because this
因为这可以用这种方式 学习
kinds of approaches are scalable to an
各种方法可以扩展到
arbitrary number of cars and you could
任意数量的汽车，你可以
imagine us plopping down the best cars
想象我们把最好的汽车扔下来
from this class together and having them
从这个班级一起并拥有它们
compete in this way the best neural
以这种方式竞争最好的神经
networks because they're full in their
网络，因为他们在他们的
greedy operation the number of networks
贪吃操作的网络数量
that can concurrently operate is fully
可以 同时运作的是完全的
scaleable there's a lot of parameters
可扩展的有很多 参数
the temporal window the layers the many
所述 时间窗口 中的层中的许多
layers types that can be added here's a
可以在 这里 添加的图层类型是 a
fully connected layer with tenure ons
完全连接的图层与任期
the activation functions all of these
激活功能所有这些
things can be customized as specified in
事物可以按照规定进行定制
the tutorial the final layer a fully
教程最后一层完全
connected layer with output a five
连接层与输出 五
regression giving the value of each of
回归给出的每一个的值
the five actions and there's a lot of
五个动作，还有很多
more specific parameters some of which
更具体的参数 其中的 一些
have this
拥有这个
just from gamma to epsilon to experience
只是从伽马到 epsilon体验
replay size to learning rate in temporal
在时间上重放大小到学习率
window the optimizer the learning rate
窗口优化器的学习率
momentum batch size l2 l1 to K for
动量批量大小l2 l1到K为
regularization and so on there's a big
正规化等等有一个很大的问题
white button that says apply code that
应用代码的白色按钮
you press that kills all the work you've
你按下它会杀死你所有的工作
done up to this point so be careful
做到这一点 所以 要小心
doing it it should be doing it only at
这样做应该 只在
the very beginning if you happen to
如果你碰巧，那一开始就是
leave your computer running in training
让你的电脑在 训练中 运行
for several days as as folks have done
人们做 了 几天
the blue training button you press and
你按下的蓝色训练按钮
it trains based on the parameters you
它根据您的参数进行训练
specify and the network state gets
指定和网络状态
shipped to the main simulation from time
从时间运到主模拟
to time so the thing you see in the
时间所以你 看到 的东西
browser as you open up the web site is
浏览器，因为你打开了网站是
running then the same network that's
然后运行相同的网络
being trained and regularly it updates
经过培训并定期更新
that network so it's getting better and
那个网络 所以它变得 更好了
better even if the training takes weeks
即使 培训需要数周， 也会更好
for you it's constantly updating the
为你 而不断更新
network you see on the left so if the
你在左边看到的网络如果是的话
car for the network that you're training
你正在训练的网络汽车
is just standing in place and not moving
只是站在 原地而不动
it's probably time to restart and change
这可能 是重新开始和改变的时候了
the parameters maybe add a few layers to
参数可能会添加 几层
your network number of iterations is
你的网络迭代次数 是
certainly an important parameter to
肯定是一个重要的参数
control and the evaluation is something
控制和评估 是一回事
we've done a lot of worked on since last
自从 上次 以来我们已经做了很多工作
year to remove the degree of randomness
一年去除随机性 程度
to remove the the incentive to submit
删除提交的动机
the same code over and over again to
相同的代码一遍又一遍 ，以
hope to produce a higher reward a higher
希望能产生较高的回报更高
evaluation score the method for
评价得分的方法
evaluation is we collect the average
评估是我们收集的平均值
speed over ten runs about 45 seconds of
速度超过 10次运行 约45 秒
game each not minutes 45 simulated
游戏每个不是分钟45模拟
seconds and there is five hundreds of
秒，有五百
those and we take the median speed of
那些和我们采取的中间速度
the 500 runs it's done server-side so
500个运行它做服务器端 ，从而
extremely difficult to cheat I urge you
我非常难以作弊
to try you can try it locally there's a
尝试你可以尝试在当地有一个
start evaluation run but that one
开始评估运行，但那一个
doesn't count that's just for you to
不计算 那 只是为了你
feel better
感觉好多了
by you network that's that should
通过你的网络那是应该的
produce a result that's very similar to
产生结果那是非常相似 的
the one we were produced on the server
我们在服务器上生成的那个
it's to build your own intuition and as
这是建立自己的直觉 和
I said we significantly reduce the
我说我们大大减少了
influence of randomness so the the score
随机性的影响因此 得分
the speed you get for the network you
你获得网络的速度
design should be very similar with every
设计应该与每个人非常相似
valuation loading is saving if the
如果是，则估值加载正在保存
network is huge and you want to switch
网络很大，你想切换
computers you can save the network it
电脑你可以保存网络吧
saves both the architecture of the
保存了两者的架构
network and the weights and the on the
网络和权重和
network and you can load it back in
网络， 你可以加载它
obviously when you load it in it's not
显然， 当你 加载它不是
saving any of the data you've already
保存您已经拥有的 任何 数据
done you can't do transfer learning with
做完你不能做转移学习
javascript in the browser yet submitting
浏览器中的javascript 还在提交
your network submit model to competition
您的网络提交竞争模型
and make sure you run training first
并确保你先进行训练
otherwise it'll be initiated the way to
否则它将开始通往
initiate it randomly and will not do so
随机 启动 ， 并 会不会这样做
well
好
you can resubmit us off and you like and
你可以重新提交我们， 你喜欢和
the highest score is what counts the
最高分是重要的
coolest part is you can load your custom
最酷的部分是你可以加载你的自定义
image specify colors and request the
图像指定颜色并请求
visualization we have not yet shown the
可视化，我们还没有表现出对
visualization but I promise you it's
可视化， 但我向你保证
going to be awesome again read the
会再次看起来很棒了
tutorial change the parameters in the
教程更改了参数
code box click apply code run training
代码框点击应用代码运行培训
everybody in this room on the way home
在回家的路上，这个房间里的每个人
on the train hopefully not in your car
在火车上希望 不在你的车里
should be able to do this in the browser
应该能够在浏览器中执行此操作
and then you can visualize request
然后 你可以看到 请求
visualization because it's an expensive
可视化，因为它是昂贵的
process you have to want it for us to do
过程 你必须要 我们这样做
it because we have to run in server-side
因为我们必须在服务器端运行
competition link is there github starter
竞争环节是github的首发
code is there and the details for those
代码是存在的，细节的那些
that truly want to win is in the archive
真正 想赢 是在存档
paper so the question that will come up
纸这样的问题 就会出现
throughout is whether these
始终是这些
reinforcement learning approaches are at
强化学习方法是在
all or rather if action planning control
全部或更确切地说是行动计划控制
is amenable to learning certainly in the
很容易在学习中学习
case of driving we can't do it alpha go
开车的情况我们不能做到这一点
zero did we can
我们能做到零
learn from scratch from self play
从自我发挥中学习
because that will result in millions of
因为这 将导致 数百万
crashes in order to learn to avoid the
崩溃是为了学会避免
crashes unless we're working like we are
除非我们像 我们 一样工作，否则会崩溃
deep crash on the RC car or we're
RC车上的严重撞击或我们是
working in a simulation so we can look
我们可以在模拟中工作
at export data we can look at driver
在出口数据我们可以看看 司机
data which we have a lot of and learn
我们有很多并且学习的数据
from it's an open question whether this
这是一个悬而未决的问题
is applicable to date and I'll bring up
适用于 约会，我会提出 来
two companies because they're both guest
两家公司，因为他们都是客人
speakers deep IRL is not involved in the
扬声器深IRL不参与
most successful robots operating in the
最成功的机器人在
real world in the case of Boston
波士顿的现实世界
Dynamics most of the perception control
动力学大部分是感知控制
and planning like in this robot does not
并且像这个机器人那样的计划没有
involve learning approaches except with
涉及学习方法，除了
minimal addition on the perception side
感知方面的最小增加
best of our knowledge and certainly the
最好的知识，当然
same is true with Wei MO as the speaker
作为演讲者， 魏薇也是如此
on Friday will talk about deep learning
周五将谈论深度学习
is used a little bit in perception on
在感知上使用了一点点
top but most of the work is done from
顶部但大部分工作都是从中完成的
the sensors and the optimization base
传感器和优化 基础
the model-based approaches trajectory
基于模型的方法轨迹
generation and optimizing which
生成和优化哪个
trajectory trajectory is best to avoid
轨迹轨迹最好 避免
collisions deep IRL is not involved and
碰撞深度IRL没有涉及和
coming back and back again
又回来了
the unexpected local POC is a high
意想不到的本地POC很高
reward which arises in all of these
在所有这些中出现的 奖励
situations and apply in the real world
情况并适用于现实 世界
so for the cat video that's pretty short
所以对于非常短的猫视频
where the cats are ringing the bell and
猫在敲钟的地方
they're learning that the ring in the
他们正在学习那个戒指
bell is is mapping to food I urge you to
贝尔正在寻求食物，我恳请 你
think about how that can evolve over
想想如何发展过来
time in unexpected ways they may not
他们可能不会 以意想不到的方式 来
have a desirable effect where the final
在决赛中有一个理想的效果
reward is in the form of food and the
奖励是以食物和食物的形式
intended effect is to ring the bell
预期的效果是响铃
that's
那是
ASAT comes in for the artificial general
ASAT为人工将军提供服务
intelligence course in two weeks that
在两周的情报课程，
something will explore extensively its
有些东西会广泛探索它
how these reinforcement learning
这些强化学习如何
planning algorithms will evolve in ways
规划算法将以 各种方式 发展
they're not expected and how we can
他们没有被期待 ，我们怎么可能
constrain them how we can design reward
限制他们如何设计奖励
functions that result in safe operation
导致安全操作的功能
so I encourage you to come to the talk
所以我鼓励你来 谈谈
on Friday at 1:00 p.m. as a reminder so
星期五下午 1点作为 提醒
1:00 p.m. not 7:00 p.m. in Stata 32 one
Stata 32中的 下午1:00而非下午7:00
two three and two the awesome talks in
两个三和两个令人敬畏的谈话
two weeks from Boston Dynamics to Ray
两周从波士顿动力学 到雷
Kurzweil and so on for AGI now tomorrow
Kurzweil 等 明天就AGI而来
we'll talk about computer vision and
我们将谈论计算机 视觉和
psyche fuse thank you everybody
psyche fuse 谢谢大家
[Applause]
[掌声]